# **WALTER TRACEY**

7606 Whitehall Dr. Dayton, OH 45459

765-580-1209 wtraceyv@gmail.com https://github.com/wtraceyv

### **Profile**

Detail-oriented Computer Science graduate with development and systems experience in various languages from school and personal projects; interested in expanding knowledge into security, systems or infrastructure, AI, game development, and other creative software tool development. Also self-taught and heavily interested in sound design and playing, recording, and mixing music of all genres.

## **Experience**

# **Elliott Tool Technologies**

## Application Developer — March 2023-Present

- Trained in programming sourced HMIs (touchscreen, human-machine interface) and Yaskawa servomotor PLCs as part of a development project
- Identifying and prioritizing work necessary to modernize IT and its relationship to other departments
- Collaborated with Engineering lead on fully automated system for gathering and analyzing data that determines Engineering effectiveness and influences bonuses

## Junior Application Developer — 2022-March 2023

- Work with internal customers to fix and enhance tools including their CRM, a complex ERP system, various other licensed tools, and custom standalone applications
- Full stack work using various languages such as HTML/CSS/JavaScript (React), .NET C# and VB, SQL, Python, shell scripting, as well as some IT tasks like server configuration
- · Drove move to integrate proper version control usage with all projects
- Documenting a relatively large, poorly documented system
- Implementing new-to-us Agile methodology in everyday work

#### GoodMedicine

### Web Dev/Media Management; Part-time remote — 2020-2023

- · Work with stakeholders, devs, and outside company reps to include new brands and maintain compliance
- · Configuring and tweaking a large eCommerce WordPress site
- Finishing and posting hundreds of products for international dietary supplement brands
- Writing some Python tools to automate my workflow for things like accessibility tags on the site

### Atrium Pro Brands, Division of Nestle Health Science

### Data Miner; Part-time remote — 2017-2019

- Studying the domain subject of nutrigenomics and the state of the art with ethics involved and what types of research will be relevant to the new supplement platform
- Integrate with science team and keep track of progress via spreadsheet
- Python web scraping for relevant articles and organizing accordingly

#### Education

- Miami University, Oxford, OH Computer Science B.S. (Honors) 2021, Magna Cum Laude
- UCHS, Liberty, IN Core 40 Honors 2017, Class Valedictorian

## **Skills**

### Languages

Proficient: HTML/CSS/JS•Bash

Intermediate: C/C++•Java•Python•Nodejs•Reactjs•SQL

Limited: PHP•C#

### Frameworks/Tools

- MERN stack
- .NET
- Any major OS
- · Godot and Unity game engines